<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
   Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
  contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
  this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
  The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
  (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
  the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

   Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
   distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
   WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
   See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
   limitations under the License.
-->
<document>
   <properties>
      <title>Release notes for Commons-Launcher 1.1</title>
      <author email="dev@commons.apache.org">Commons Documentation Team</author>
      <revision>$Id$</revision>
   </properties>

   <body>
     <section name="Release notes for Commons-Launcher 1.1">
<p>
Launcher was imported into jakarta commons almost 2 years ago (25 okt 2002) but never had a release. 
</p>

<p>The Launcher Component is designed to be a cross platform Java
application launcher.</p>
<p>The original Java classes come from the Jakarta Tomcat 4.0 project.</p>
<p>
Tomcat has been shipping the 1.0-dev version from CVS for a while now
(definitely more than a year), so this official release will be labaled 1.1
to avoid confusion.
</p>

<!-- BEGIN include homepage -->
<p>
Commons-launcher eliminates the need for a batch or shell script to launch a 
Java class. Some situations where elimination of a batch or shell script may 
be desirable are:
<ul>
  <li>You want to avoid having to determining where certain application paths
  are e.g. your application's home directory, etc. Determining this
  dynamically in a Windows batch scripts is very tricky on some versions of
  Windows or when softlinks are used on Unix platforms.</li>
  <li>You want to avoid having to handle native file and path separators or
  native path quoting issues.</li>
  <li>You need to enforce certain system properties e.g.
  <code>java.endorsed.dirs</code> when running with JDK 1.4.</li>
  <li>You want to allow users to pass in custom JVM arguments or system
  properties without having to parse and reorder arguments in your script.
  This can be tricky and/or messy in batch and shell scripts.</li>
  <li>You want to bootstrap system properties from a configuration file instead
  hard-coding them in your batch and shell scripts.</li>
  <li>You want to provide localized error messages which is very tricky to do
  in batch and shell scripts.</li>
  </ul>
</p>
<!-- END include -->

<p>
For more information consult the 
<a href="http://commons.apache.org/launcher/">Commons-Launcher website</a>.
</p>
</section>
</body>
</document>

